Preliminary Guide to the Equal Employment Office records, 1974-2006 RG0035
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Equal Employment Office records
1974-2006
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
George Washington University. Office of Equal Employment Opportunity
RG0035
123.75 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include, affirmative action info and records, affirmative action plans, promotion recommendations, recruitment plans and summaries, personnel files (complaints), civil actions, litigation files, personnel program slides, academic dishonesty, litigation files, IGH (Informal Grievance Hearing) files, restricted grievance files, charges of discrimination, budget, correspondence, family and medical leave act. These files range in date from 1974-2006.
Restrictions on Access
This entire collection is closed to research for 75 years from date of record creation. Please see the University Archivist if you have any questions.
Acquisition Information
Materials were transferred to the University Archives by the Office of Equal Employment.
Historical Note
The Office of Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO), formally known as the Office of Equal Employment Activities (EEA), sets guidelines for the affirmative action plan which was instituted at The George Washington University in 1970. The EEO reports to the Associate Vice President of Human Resources.
The mission of the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity (EEO) is to enhance the University's fundamental commitment to equality and fairness in recruitment, selection, and employment at the University by applying the tenets of the University's affirmative action programs to expand and support diversity throughout the University. Additionally, the University guarantees an impartial, non-adversarial setting where grievances can be resolved through counseling and mediation, and by providing related training to staff employees.
The responsibilities of the Office of Equal Employment Opportunity include the resolution of the following situations: faculty and staff requests for reasonable accommodation under the Americans with Disabilities act for employment matters, staff requests for religious accommodations, and staff internal discrimination complaints.
Additionally, the EEO is responsible to write the University's affirmative action program for faculty and staff, implement staff training programs on EEO regarding affirmative action, sexual harassment, diversity and disability issues. Finally, the EEO is responsible to respond to external administrative agency complaints filed by staff, and to serve as lead employer for the District of Columbia Business Leadership Network (DCBLN).
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include, affirmative action info and records, affirmative action plans, promotion recommendations, recruitment plans and summaries, personnel files (complaints), civil actions, litigation files, personnel program slides, academic dishonesty, litigation files, IGH (Informal Grievance Hearing) files, restricted grievance files, charges of discrimination, budget, correspondence, family and medical leave act. These files range in date from 1974-2006 and were transferred to the University Archives by the Office of Equal Employment.
Collection Organization
Organized into nineteen series: Affirmative Action plan, Personnel files, three series of informal grievance hearings, recruitment charges, twelve series of Office files, and recruitment plans and grievances.
Budget; Litigation; Affirmative action programs; Color slides
- Affirmative Action plans, 1974-1976; RG0035 Series 1; .25 Linear feet (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  This series includes affirmative action plans for the George Washington University. They range in date from 1974-76.
  Formerly vertical files
  - Affirmative Action Plans, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Equal Employment Activities Office, 05/15/1974-09/22/1977 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Office files, 1974-1983; RG0035 Series 2; 2 Linear feet
  Affirmative action and EEA info and records, 1974-83.
  Formerly ACC#60
  This series has a paper container list in the reading room, please ask staff for assistance.
- Office files, 1986-1988; RG0035 Series 3; 1 Linear foot
  This series contains affirmative action plans, promotion recommendations, and recruitment data. This material covers the dates 1986-88.
  Formerly ACC#76
- Office files, 1984-1988; RG0035 Series 4; 7 Linear feet
  This series contains affirmative action plan and supporting information. The material dates from 1984-88.
  Formerly ACC#77
- Personnel files, RG0035 Series 5; 5 Linear feet
  This series contains personnel files (complaints).
  Formerly ACC#180
- Office files, 1983-1992; RG0035 Series 6; 10 Linear feet
  This series contains civil actions, litigation, black history, and committees records. The material covers the dates 1983-92.
  Formerly ACC#334
- Office files, 1984-1992; RG0035 Series 7; 8 Linear feet
  This series contains confidential office files and personnel program slides. The material covers the dates 1984-92.
  Formerly ACC#347
- Office files, 1990-1992; RG0035 Series 8; 1 Linear foot
  This series contains files related to academic dishonesty and litigation. These records date from 1990-92.
  Formerly ACC#363
- Informal grievance hearings, RG0035 Series 9; 1 Linear foot
  This series contains files related to IGH, informal grievance hearings.
  Formerly ACC#364
- Grievance files, 1987-1990; RG0035 Series 10; 1 Linear feet
  This series contains grievance files. The files date from 1987-90.
  Formerly ACC#380
- Office files, RG0035 Series 11; 7 Linear feet
  This series contains files related to recruitment, nursing staff, the Banner system, and litigation.
  Formerly ACC#427
- Office files, RG0035 Series 12; 4 Linear feet
  The material in this series relates to DHR, EEOC, and other charges, reading files, budget, training, and the Family and Medical Leave Act.
  Formerly ACC#574
- Informal grievance hearings and discrimination charges, RG0035 Series 13; 3 Linear feet
  This series contains charges of discrimination, and IGH (informal grievance hearing) charges.
  Formerly ACC#583
- Recruitment charges, 1994-1996; RG0035 Series 14; 3 Linear feet
  This series contains files related to recruitment charges. This material dates from 1994-96.
  Formerly ACC#586
  This series has a container list in electronic form, please ask staff for assistance.
- Office files, RG0035 Series 15; 3 Linear feet
  This series contains records related to IGH (informal grievance hearing), EEOC, DHR, FGH and charges of descriminations.
  Formerly ACC#621
- Office files, 1983-1993; RG0035 Series 16; 15 Linear feet
  This series contains records related to equal employment activities, affirmative action plans, training, recruitment plans and summaries, budget, and EEOC charges. These records date from 1983-93.
  Formerly ACC#760
- Office files, 1985-2000; RG0035 Series 17; 9 Linear feet
  This series contains EEOC charges, recruitment plans and summaries, budget, and correspondence. This material is dated from 1985-2000.
  Formerly ACC#793
- Office files, 1994-2002; RG0035 Series 18; 12 Linear feet
  This series contains EEOC files. These files date from 1994-2002.
  Formerly ACC#1036
- Recruitment plans and grievances, 1998-2006; RG0035 Series 19; 31.5 Linear feet
  This series contains EEOC files. These files date from 1998-2006.